FIMBER UCHENNA

GitHub: https://www.github.com/uchenna631 LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/fimber-uchenna

Email: <u>uchenna631@gmail.com</u> Address: Kent, United Kingdom Phone: +44793 433 9221

Profile

A junior full-stack software developer, particularly interested in a graduate role where I can learn and hone my skills in software development while contributing to a team.

I am an avid reader, a quick learner, and passionate about exploring new technologies. Previously, I was a Field Service Engineer with two years of experience in the telecommunications sector and three years of experience in the production sector as an Operator.

Skills

Back-End Technology

Python

Front-End Technologies

- HTML5
- CSS3
- JavaScript
- Bootsrap

Editors/IDEs

- Visual Studio Code
- Sublime 3
- Gitpod

Other Technical Skills

- Virtual Environments like Slack
- Git & GitHub
- Office 365
- Google Suite

Soft Skills

- Customer Service
- Eager to learn
- Critical & Abstract thinking

- Strong attention to detail
- Team player
- Positive attitude
- Phone and email etiquette
- Work well under pressure

Spoken languages

- Igbo Native
- English Proficient

Project Accomplishments

HoliDates – 5 Days Hackathon Challenge organized by Code Institute – Ireland – February 2022. Collaborated with my team remotely to create a romantic getaway/honeymoon destination site. View live site – HoliDates

Ogbunike Caves – Code Institute's Portfolio Project I – Ireland – February 2022.

Successfully created a static website for a natural resort center, Ogbunike Caves, to showcase the knowledge and understanding of HTML5 & CSS3. See live link – <u>OGBUNIKE CAVES</u>

Asset Tagging and Asset Capture – IHS Towers Limited – Nigeria – September – December 2020 Successfully planned and executed asset tagging and capturing of all passive infrastructure in 96 sites into IHS infrastructure database using Microsoft Power Apps.

MTN Nigeria 4G Network Migration – IHS Towers Limited – Nigeria – January 2021 – August 2021 Successfully planned and executed the power upgrade and network migration of 58 3G sites to 4G technology with minimal network degradation – 100% PA, 99.25% PTTCH.

Work Experience

Field Service Engineer – IHS Towers Limited – Nigeria – July 2019 – August 2021

- Planned and supervised operation and routine maintenance 96 cell sites.
- Trained and mentored team of 9 maintenance Technicians.
- Maintained excellent customer relationship, engagement and support.
- Kept maintenance and operational records.
- Reported to the Field Operations Manager

Production Operator – Emenite Limited – Nigeria – August 2016 – June 2019

- Ensured the production of high-quality silica.
- Kept production record and reported to the Production Supervisor.

Supervisor – Ani-Lion Resources Nigeria Limited – Nigeria – September 2014 – June 2016

- Supervised projects and maintenance activities.
- Kept record.
- Reported to the Managing Director.

Education

•

- Learned about data structures, algorithms and the basics of programming.
- Learned about version control, agile software development and documentation.
- Learned HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
- Learning Python, jQuery and Bootstrap.

Automate the Boring Stuff with Python – Udemy - Online – July – November, 2021

 Learned the fundamentals of Computer Programming, Data Structures, Algorithm and Python programming.

Electrical Engineering – University of Nigeria, Nsukka - Nigeria – October 2009 – August 2014. - 3.64/5.0 CGPA

• Learned the principles of Electrical Engineering, Electrical Machines, Power Systems and Power Control

Hobbies and Interests

Hackathons.

Collaboration on Slack

References

References are available upon request

NOTE: PA – power availability. PTTCH – percentage traffic channel